everbank.com 2009-12-25

# Privacy and Security | EverBank

  1. HOME
  2. ABOUT US
  3. PRIVACY AND SECURITY

  * Information Collection and Sharing
    * ### Notice of Information Collection

EverBank collects and retains information about its consumers from many sources, including:

      1. Account applications or other forms you submit to EverBank, including information about your age, gender, marital status, number of dependents, assets, debts, income, employment information, and address;
      2. Transactions you conduct with or through EverBank, EverBank's affiliates, or others, such as account balances, payment due dates, payment record, account status, and information you give to EverBank in any telephone call, letter, or e-mail;
      3. Reports from Consumer Reporting Agencies, including information about your credit worthiness, financial circumstances, and credit history, including any bankruptcies or foreclosures.

Unless this information is public, it is known as "nonpublic personal information." EverBank uses the information it collects in the course of its relationship with you, to process your account application(s), provide you with services, and offer information to you about your account. EverBank also uses the information it collects to analyze your situation using traditional banking practices, and to tailor your experience at the EverBank website, displaying content and images EverBank believes may be of interest to you.

In addition to the nonpublic personal information described above, EverBank collects information in other ways:

      1. EverBank uses your IP address to help diagnose problems with its server, and to administer the website. An IP address is like a telephone number for a computer on the Internet. Just as one can locate a person’s or business' phone number in the telephone book, computers can locate a website’s IP address using a Domain Name Service Server. EverBank also uses your IP address to help identify you and your browser as you move throughout the EverBank website, and to gather broad demographic information. In many cases, this allows EverBank to present a convenient, more customized website to you;
      2. EverBank's site uses cookies to keep track of you as you move through the website. EverBank uses cookies to deliver content specific to your interests, and to provide access to the secure banking functions available on the EverBank  
website. Cookies are discussed in more detail below.
  * Information Security
    * Protecting your information is important to EverBank. To protect your information, EverBank has instituted policies, procedures, employee training, and communication programs. Examples of how EverBank protects your information include, but are not limited to, the following:

      1. Restricting physical or other access to your nonpublic personal information to persons with a legitimate business need to know the information in order to process or service your account(s);
      2. Contractually requiring third parties doing business with EverBank to comply with all privacy and security laws;
      3. Maintaining physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards that comply with federal standards to guard your nonpublic personal information.

You can help EverBank protect your information by keeping your account information, particularly personal identification numbers (PINs) and other access codes, confidential. And whenever you need to e-mail us personal information, be sure to send a secure e-mail.

  * Public Forums
    * The EverBank website may make chat rooms, forums, message boards, and/or news groups available to its users. Please remember that any information disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information. EverBank is not responsible for content posted by third parties to public forums. EverBank reserves the right to discontinue offering public forums at any time and for any reason.
  * Encrypted Email
    * Encrypted e-mail not only provides authentication but also protects your privacy. If a message is properly encrypted, no one on the public Internet can read your message to EverBank. Encryption software "scrambles" the message so that only the intended recipient can read the message. Encrypted e-mail often supports a digital signature within the same process. When combined, encryption and a digital signature allow you to obtain both authentication and privacy. EverBank encourages and supports the use of encrypted messages for communication with the Bank. As an account holder, you will have access from within the EverBank Online Financial Center, to an encrypted, secure web-based e-mail system. That system will allow you to communicate via a secured channel with EverBank Customer Care Specialists.
  * Notice of Information Sharing
    * EverBank may share the information it collects and retains, as described above, with EverBank's affiliates (companies in our corporate family) or with unaffiliated third parties (such as credit reporting agencies, financial service providers, insurance companies, and other service providers). You understand and agree that EverBank may share this information with affiliates and unaffiliated third parties in the following instances:  

      1. To verify the existence and condition of your accounts or loans for a credit bureau (consumer reporting agency) for purposes of recording your credit history with EverBank;
      2. When it is necessary or helpful in completing transactions, such as to verify the existence and condition of your account for a merchant or bank for purposes of transactions you have requested using your account;
      3. To comply with applicable governmental reporting or legal processes (such as court orders, subpoenas, or governmental requests) that EverBank reasonably believes to be valid or required;
      4. With companies that perform services on EverBank's behalf;
      5. When investigating a loss involving EverBank and another financial institution, or to local, state, or federal authorities if EverBank believes that a crime may have been committed involving your account; or
      6. When permitted or required by law, regulation, or court order; or
      7. When you give EverBank permission to do so.
Except as disclosed in this document, EverBank does not share personally identifiable, non-public information about you with unaffiliated third parties for any other purpose. In addition to the sharing described above, the law also allows us to share information about our transactions or experiences with you with our affiliates, such as your account history for any reason including for marketing. Unless you exercise your right to restrict EverBank's ability to share information about you as described in the “Opt-Out Rights” section below, we may also share with our affiliates other information that you provide to us or that we obtain from unaffiliated third parties (such as credit history, income, credit references, and employment history) for any reason including marketing.

### For Vermont Residents Only: 

According to Vermont law, while we may share information about our transactions or experiences with you with our affiliates, EverBank will not share information that you provide to us or that we obtain from third parties (such as credit history, income, credit references, and employment history) about Vermont residents within the EverBank family, without your consent unless otherwise required or permitted by law. Vermont residents do not need to opt-out to implement their rights under this Privacy Policy.

### Information Collected in Surveys or Contests

From time to time, EverBank's website may utilize online surveys or run contests that ask you for contact information (such as your e-mail address) and demographic information (e.g., ZIP code, age, or income level). EverBank uses contact data from its surveys and contests to send you information about EverBank, and promotional material from certain partners. Your contact information is used to contact you when necessary. You may request no further mailings; see the "How to Refuse Further Mailings" subsection below. Demographic and profile data is also collected at EverBank's website. EverBank uses this data to tailor its visitor website experience, providing you content which EverBank believes may be of interest to you, and to display content based on your preferences.

### Other Information Collection

When you use EverBank's websites, EverBank may use cookies to gather information about you and your use of its site. Cookies are small text files or text identifiers that are placed on your computer by EverBank (along with many other Internet websites). Cookies are used to identify a particular visitor’s browser, which in many cases equates to an individual. EverBank believes that by using cookies it is able to provide you with a better experience and better service when you visit the EverBank website. Cookies are not destructive or disruptive to your computer. EverBank also believes that these benign bits of information do not have the ability to contain malicious programs or viruses that could damage your computer. If you choose, you may set your Web browser to warn you before you accept a cookie and choose each time if you want to accept the cookie. You may also choose to obtain software that operates in conjunction with your browser to control cookie acceptance. Some portions of the EverBank website require the use of cookies for proper function so that EverBank can provide you with a secure environment for certain financial transactions. 
  * Links to Other Sites
    * The EverBank website contains links to other sites, including sites for affiliates of EverBank. EverBank is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites. Please review the privacy statement found on each of these sites when linking through.
  * Former Customers
    * EverBank follows the same practices described above in its collection and disclosure of nonpublic personal information relating to you if you were a former customer.
  * Notice of Your Opportunity to Opt-Out of Information Sharing
    * EverBank may share with its affiliates any information about its direct transactions and experiences with you. However, you may elect to opt-out of EverBank sharing other information that it collects and retains about you, as described above, with its affiliates as noted above, Vermont residents do not need to opt-out as the sharing of information other than transactions and experience information is limited by Vermont law. See special notice for Vermont residents above.

To opt-out of information sharing with EverBank affiliates, you may send an e-mail to: optout@everbank.com with “Privacy Opt-Out” in the subject line and include your name and telephone number (do not send any sensitive information via e-mail).

Alternatively, you may call the following toll free number: **888.882.EVER (3837), Option 4**

### How to Refuse Further Mailings

EverBank's website provides you with the opportunity to opt out of receiving communications from EverBank and its partners. If you do not wish to receive future communications, or you no longer wish to receive EverBank's services, you may request that EverBank remove your information from its database, using one of the following options:  

      1. You may send an e-mail to:   optout@everbank.com (do not send any sensitive information via e-mail).
      2. You may send mail to the following postal address: 

    **Security and Privacy-Opt Out**
    EverBank
    11 Oval Drive, Suite 107
    Islandia, NY 11749-1416
See the Information Collection and Sharing subsection above for information on how to request that EverBank not share certain aspects of your information. 
  * Privacy Issues Contact Information
    * EverBank's website gives you the opportunity to discuss privacy issues or report anything that you consider unusual or inappropriate. If you have such an issue, you may contact EverBank in one of the following ways: 
      1. **By phone:** 888.882.EVER (3837), Option 4
      2. **By e-mail:**   privacy@everbank.com
      3. **By mail:**

    Security and Privacy
    EverBank
    11 Oval Drive, Suite 107
    Islandia, NY 11749-1416

NOTE: The preceding discussion of privacy and security applies only to information about your deposit and/or credit card account(s) you maintain for your personal or family use and related dealings with EverBank®. To the extent that you may have other accounts or relationships with EverBank or any of EverBank's other divisions or affiliates (including EverBank's National Home Loan Group or EverHome® Mortgage Company), this privacy policy does not cover those relationships.

Banking is all about trust, security, privacy, and confidence. EverBank designed its business with your privacy in mind and will continue this tradition by providing you with security and privacy protection. So that you understand exactly where EverBank stands on these important topics, we have created this document for you to review. Please take time to look over this Privacy Statement and contact a Customer Care Specialist with questions or for clarification.

  1.  
  2. EverBank, EverHome, the EverBank Infinity Sphere and EverBank logo are proprietary service marks of EverBank. All rights reserved.
